- Two trains, two chapters to tell.
兩列火車 兩個不同的篇章
One runs hot and fast.
一列高速飛馳
The other lumbers slow...
另一列蹣跚而行
Cold-cast in Wilford's iron grip...
那是威爾福德鐵腕掌控下的列車
An armored tortoise plodding after a hare...
一只在兔子身后策劃陰謀的 武裝的烏龜
Everyone under a single thumb...
所有人都受同一個人控制
Serving a single obsession...
服務于同一個偏執的目標…
To retake the pirates and exact his revenge.
奪回被盜的東西 實施他的報復
I can smell them.
我能聞到他們的氣味
Layton took my engine through here
從結冰情況來看
about a month ago, judging by the ice buildup.
大約一個月前 雷頓把我的機車帶到這里來過
Practically on their heels.
我們已經緊隨其后了
You see?
看到沒
Like old footprints in the snow.
就像雪地里的足跡一樣
Set switch for the south fork, Engineer.
工程師 轉到往南去的岔路上
We'll get it back, Jupe, whatever it takes.
我們會把它奪回來的 朱庇特 不惜任何代價
- Inside, it's a backwards world.
列車里是一個倒退的世界
Only one class now,
如今只有一個階級了
the working class, freezing, stitching,
那就是工人階級
fixing, suffering.
縫補修葺 忍凍受罪
- Hey, this isn't a pass-through.
嘿 這里不是過道
- Winnipeg. - Message for the top.
-溫妮佩 -有給頭兒捎的信
- But frostbitten fingers hold fast.
不過 挨凍的人們更會抱作一團
Deep in the iced-over bowels where Wilford never treads...
在寒冰深處 威爾福德從不涉足的地方
A spark still lives:
依然有一絲火花在閃耀
the resistance,
那就是抵抗軍
nurtured and protected by the bravest of the brave.
由勇者中的勇者培養并守護著
- Message for the tippity-top.
給頭兒捎的信
- I didn't hear the password, Mr. Pike.
派克先生 你沒說暗號
I expect more from my second in command.
你是我的二把手 我對你的期望比這要高
They picked up sign of Snowpiercer.
他們發現了雪國列車的蹤跡
We turned south, back on the main line.
我們已轉向南面 回到了主軌道上
Oh, thank God for that.
謝天謝地
This is the first proof we've had that they are still alive in 32 days.
32天了 這是第一個 證明他們還活著的消息
They must--they must have their reasons for all this traipsing about.
他們這樣到處閑轉 一定有他們的原因
I mean, if Melanie's aboard--
如果梅蘭妮在列車上的話
We don't know.
這又說不定的
- You ever think, Ruth, all alone down here at night,
魯絲 晚上你一個人 待在這下面時 有沒有想過
that since Layton bailed on us in the first place,
既然當初是雷頓拋下了我們
he might never come back?
他可能永遠都不會回來了
No, I don't.
沒想過
And neither do you, or you wouldn't be in the resistance.
你也沒有 否則你不會加入抵抗軍
- So antibiotics for the seamstresses. They'll need them,
好了 這些抗生素給裁縫們 她們會需要的
all jammed up together in that sweatshop.
大家都擠在那個血汗工廠里
It's these little things that will keep us sane, Mr. Pike.
這些小小的補給品能讓我們保持理智
The passengers can survive all of this if we can ease their journey.
如果我們能讓旅途稍微舒服點 乘客們就能熬過這一關
And keep them ready for Mr. Layton's return.
讓他們為雷頓先生的歸來做好準備
- The heart of hope still beats aboard Wilford's rolling gulag,
威爾福德1023節車廂長的集中營 轟隆前行
1,023 cars long.
在車上依然跳動著滿懷希望的心
Okay. Should be clear of track contaminants.
好 這里應該不會有軌道污染物了
I'm gonna start pulling ice samples.
我要開始采集冰樣了
How's it looking?
外面看上去怎么樣
- Palm trees, golden sands.
棕櫚樹 金沙灘
Gotta catch me some North Korean waves.
我得去趕朝鮮的海浪
- Nice. I'll grab my board. I'll be right out, bro.
真不錯 我去拿一下沖浪板 馬上就出去 兄弟
- Let him focus.
讓他集中精力
- I'm keeping him calm. - You're distracting him.
-我是在幫他保持冷靜 -你是在讓他分心
- Ben, the suit's at 22 minutes. Your heart rate's good.
本 你的防護服還能堅持22分鐘 你的心率正常
You steady on, okay?
不用緊張 好嗎
Copy that.
收到
Engine any happier?
引擎運轉得好點了嗎
- We're venting, but still too hot.
在排放燃料 但還是過熱
How's it looking?
外面的情況如何
Oh, minus 86.
“零下86攝氏度”
Oh, well, I'm sure glad we came all this way.
好吧 虧我們還大老遠跑來這里
- Well, don't mistake the weather for the climate.
別把天氣和氣候的概念搞混了
Ben's samples will show us the full picture.
本采集的樣本會顯示氣候的全貌
We're looking for trends.
我們是在尋找趨勢
- I thought we were looking for a place to live.
我還以為我們是在找宜居的地方
The model likes this spot. Let's just wait for the results.
模型說這里是合適地點 等采樣結果出來再說
Oh, the model.
“模型”
- Hey, Till, remember how much the model liked Sulawesi?
嘿 提爾 還記得之前 模型說蘇拉威西島很合適嗎
Yeah, I do.
記得
Six months of going around the world with nothing to show for it.
我們環行世界六個月了 卻沒拿得出手的成績
- And we learned something from every stop.
每一次停留 我們都了解到了新信息
Think of them as data points.  Okay, Professor Layton.
-就把它們當作是數據點嘛 -行 雷頓教授
- They were not frozen hellscapes. They were data points.
那些不是冰凍的地獄 而是數據點
Correct.
沒錯
Shit.
糟糕
- I need to talk to him. - Okay.
-我需要跟他通話 -好
- Ben, we just blew a thermal switch on the main line.
本 主管道上的一個熱敏開關壞了
- It's gotta be an error. - It isn't.
-準是誤報 -不是的
We came in too rich. I told you that.
我跟你說過 我們的空燃比太小了
- Just discharge the excess, Alex. She'll rebalance.
把多余的燃料排出去就行 艾莉 引擎自己會調整的
If I discharge any more, we won't be able to get going again.
若再繼續排放燃料 我們就會啟動不了了
We have to abort. Pull him in.
我們必須放棄行動 讓他回來
She's wrong, Layton. She can ride the levels.
別聽她的 雷頓 她能調整好空燃比的
Ten more minutes.
再給我十分鐘
- We're burning up. We need to go right now.
我們在大量耗費燃料 我們得馬上啟程
Do what you can.
盡你所能穩住引擎
- I told him we came in too rich.
我跟他說了空燃比太小
Okay.
好吧
Everything's under control.
一切盡在掌握之中
- Ben, just stay on task. Okay?
本 你繼續完成任務 好嗎
Hey.
嗨
She touchy this morning?
她今天早上發過脾氣嗎
- Scathing. So mean.
非常尖酸刻薄
- Sykes is on her way. - Great.
-賽克斯馬上就到 -很好
Why have we stopped again?
我們為什么又停下了
You know, they're not gonna find an oasis. - You know that.
他們找不到綠洲的 這你很清楚
- I don't know anything. It's easier that way.
我什么都不清楚 這樣更容易些
- Ugh, know no one, feel nothing. You're a woman alone, my jailer.
跟誰都不熟 什么感覺都沒有 我的囚犯 你是個孤獨的女人
Well, at least I got you.
至少我還有你
You gonna be civil, or do you want me to feed you in there?
你是想規規矩矩地在外面吃呢 還是想在里面吃
Monsters first.
禽獸優先
- No, please. - No.
-不 請吧 -不要
- Okay. Today's dwindling selection.
好了 能選的越來越少 這是今天的選擇
We have the boeuf bourguignon,
我們有紅酒燉牛肉
the carbonara, the dreaded chicken mushroom bag,
培根蛋醬意面、可怕的蘑菇雞肉套餐
and the last Thai vegetable.
還有最后一份泰式蔬菜
- You seem to enjoy working for these pirates.
給這些鐵路強盜干活 你好像挺開心
- Just a POW doing my time, Audrey.
奧德麗 我只是個服刑中的戰俘而已
- Well, he'd be disgusted with your cooperation.
你這么配合他們 他會惡心死的
Can you please?
能別拌嘴了嗎
- If nobody wants the Thai vegetable... - Just give me the carbonara, Martin.
-如果沒人想要泰式蔬菜… -馬汀 給我培根蛋醬意面
Carbonara, it's the worst.
培根蛋醬意面是最難吃的
- Ben? Ben, the wind's picking up. It looks like there's a front coming in.
本 風開始大了 看來有冷鋒要來了
- Copy that. I'm on my way back.
收到 我這就回去
- How's Alex?
艾莉那里情況如何
- Alex, status.
艾莉 匯報情況
We're not actively on fire.
引擎沒有著火
Tell him to hurry.
讓他動作快一點
- She says she took your advice and everything's working out.
她說她聽了你的建議 一切運作正常
So much blown snow.
這里有很多飄雪
A lot of wind comes through this basin.
有大量的風吹過這片盆地
- Well, that's good, though, right?
這是好事 對嗎
Could be.
可能是
Might be our warm spot stirring things up.
可能是模型測到的暖點引起的
- Ben. - Ben?
-本  -本
- Ben. - Ben, come in, Ben.
-本  -本 收到請回答 本
- I can't see him. - Ben.
-我看不到他了 -本
- Ben! Ben, do you copy? Ben.
本 聽到我說話了沒 本
Ben, come in.
本 聽到沒有
The bit I don't get, Bess,
貝絲 有件事我不明白
when we return to Wilford with your precious climate model,
等把你們那寶貝氣候模型 帶回給威爾福德之后
what happens then?
你們打算怎樣
Negotiations.
談判
Both trains want to reconnect.
兩列列車都想重新連接
- Yeah. Hostage negotiations first.
沒錯 先談交換人質的事
You for Zarah.
用你換扎拉
- Yeah, but then what?
行 然后呢
- Wilford's 2,700 to your 7?
用你們這里的七個人 換威爾福德手里的2700個
He's not gonna take too kindly to a traitor and a stowaway.
對叛徒和偷渡者 他可不會客氣
How am I a stowaway?
我怎么成偷渡者了
I woke up from a nap in my carriage and the train was gone,
我當時在自己的車廂里打盹 醒來時列車已經不見了
along with my husband and my twin boys.
連同我的老公和雙胞胎兒子一起沒了
Till here.
我是提爾
- Yeah, I need you to lock them down and get up here.
你得把他們關起來 然后到上面來
- What's up? - Nothing they need to know about.
-出什么事了  -沒什么是他們需要知道的
- All right. On my way.
好 我這就去
Ben, do you read?
本 聽到沒有
All right, that's lunch. Martin, lock her up.
好了 午飯結束 馬汀 把她關起來
- Is something wrong? - Move, go.
-出什么事了嗎  -動起來 快
- Hey, I saw Ben going outside earlier. - Do you need help?
嘿 我之前看到本出去了 你們需要幫忙嗎
- No, everything's good. We're good.
不用 一切都好 我們沒事
On it.
這就去
- Till. Hey,
提爾 嘿
what's going on?
出什么事了
You stay in your quarters.
你們待在自己的房間里
Wait till the engine gives the all-clear.
等著機車給出故障排除的指示
- That's it? - Yep.
-就這樣  -是的
I'm going out there. - No, you're not. I'm going.
-我要出去看看 -你不能去 我去
- Neither of you are going anywhere.
你們倆都不能出去
We can't stay here. Ben.
我們不能待在這里 本
Ben, do you copy? We are not leaving him.
-本 聽到了沒  -我們不能撇下他
- Layton, if we don't get rolling right now, we will melt down.
雷頓 如果現在不啟動 引擎會燒壞的
How long do you need?
你需要多少時間
- 8 minutes to get up to speed,
八分鐘啟動加速
10 to 12 minutes to run a discharge sequence.
10到12分鐘運行燃料釋放程序
- Great. Go. - And leave you outside?
-很好 開始吧 -把你丟在外面嗎
- The breach suits have 30 minutes. You go, you come back for me.
搶修員的防護服能維持30分鐘 你啟動列車 然后再回來找我
- You are staying here. - Yeah. Like, hell I am.
-你得留下 -聽你的才怪
It's not a discussion, Josie.
沒什么可討論的
If all three of us get in trouble out there, there's no one left for off-train work.
如果我們三個都出了事 就沒人能完成戶外任務了
- Yeah, well, I'll make sure that doesn't happen.
我會確保這情況不會發生
- You know, one time,
就這么一次
just for a change of pace, you could respect the chain of command.
麻煩你改變一下習慣 服從指揮吧
Chain of command?
“服從指揮”
Layton, this isn't a battleship. It's a bloody life raft.
雷頓 這不是艘戰艦 而是個救生筏
And you're staying on it.
你得留在筏上
- Ben shouldn't even be out there.
本根本就不該出去
- He knew what he was getting into. - Yeah. Chasing Melanie's ghost.
-他知道自己在做什么 -是呀 追逐梅蘭妮的鬼魂
Her theory.
是驗證她的理論
We all agreed.
我們都說好的
We find New Eden, then we go back for the others.
找到新伊甸園 再回去接大伙兒
- And what if there is no New Eden?
萬一沒有新伊甸園呢
What if she's wrong?
萬一她錯了呢
Guess we just all go down with her, eh?
我們就跟她一起完蛋
- Till, you're gonna have to pilot us out of here.
提爾 你得負責駕駛 把我們帶出這里
- Me? Why?
我 為什么
- Because I need to go deal with that.
因為我得處理這個
- What?
什么
Oh, Jesus. Jesus.
老天
Yeah, okay. I--I got it.
行 好 交給我了
- You're starting to believe your own hype. You do know that, don't you?
你那些天花亂墜的話 連自己都開始信了 你知道的吧
- I'm just trying to keep everyone alive.
我只是在努力讓大家都活下去
Yep. We know. Our great savior.
對 我們知道 你是我們偉大的救世主
Never my words.
我從沒這么說過
- I was there at the beginning in The Tail, in the muck and the shit.
我從一開始就在末等車廂 臟的臭的我都經歷過
I know who you are.
我知道你的為人
- You encouraged me to be a leader.
當初是你鼓勵我當領袖的
- Not for this.
不是領導這個
Didn't ask for any of this.
這都不是我想要的
- Engine, we're at the bay door. Release the safety.
機車 我們在艙門口了 打開安全閘
Uh, copy.
收到
Bay door safety?
艙門安全閘在哪兒
System panel, top right.
在系統面板的右上角
Josie, be careful.
喬西 當心點
- Yeah.
嗯
Yeah, you too.
好 你也是
You see anything?
看到什么了嗎
We're on the wrong side.
他們在另一邊 這里看不到
Well, we've been stopped for an awfully long time, haven't we?
我們已經停了很長時間了 不是嗎
Engine, we're clear. - Okay. Copy.
-機車 我們已下車了 -好 收到
They're clear!
他們下車了
- Okay. Take us up to 20.
你能啟動 加速到20嗎
- Easy! Easy.
悠著點
- This is the general consolidated ledger.
這是總的合并分類帳
And you can see where the quartermaster detected pilfering.
從中可以看到 司務長是在哪個環節 發現偷竊行為的
- Cleverly dispersed along the supply chain.
巧妙地分攤到了供應鏈的各個環節
- Laytonites, or what's left of them.
是雷頓的余黨干的
- Yeah. Someone's playing Robin Hood.
沒錯 有人在扮演羅賓漢呢
Zarah. Zarah. How are you feeling?
扎拉 你感覺如何
Enormous. - I'm fine, thank you. Oh, good.
-非常龐大 我挺好 謝謝關心 -很好…
- I have the engineering report, Javi.
哈維 我拿到了工程部的報告
- I'll take that. - Let's hear it from her.
-給我吧 -我們來聽她說吧
I appreciate how you deliver bad news, Zarah.
扎拉 我很欣賞你傳遞壞消息的方式
Always a clear-eyed view.
你總能保持心明眼亮
- So, then,
那好吧
your water pipes are still frozen. Most of Second and parts of Third.
大部分二等車廂 和部分三等車廂的水管還凍著
And Ag-Sec output is down again, but only by 6% this week.
農業區的產量又下降了 不過本周只下降了6%
- This is pilfering. I was--
這是因為有人盜竊…
- And last night, 43 sleepers and The Chains lost heat completely.
昨晚 43個休眠者 以及串連區的供熱完全斷了
162 passengers remain evacuated.
仍有162名乘客處于疏散狀態
- Well, if we can't keep them all warm at once,
如果我們沒法同時為所有人供暖
they'll just have to be miserable in shifts.
那他們就得分批挨凍
We'll cut First Class.
拋棄頭等車廂呀
Out of the question.
不行
- Well, you did decommission it, Joseph. It's empty and frozen. - Cut the weight.
約瑟夫 你已經將其棄置 都空了 又結了冰 拋棄它可以減輕負擔
- I will restore First to glory when I get my engine back-- and Audrey with it.
等我把機車和奧德麗奪回來之后 就會讓頭等車廂重現輝煌
- Perhaps there's another way to conserve energy. - Like a cull.
也許有其他節約能源的方法 比如選擇性宰殺
- No, Kevin, you ghoul.
不行 凱文 你這個食人魔
- Please berate him. Remind him there are rules.
請教訓一下他 提醒他這里是有規矩的
Sorry to disappoint, Kevin.
很抱歉得讓你失望了 凱文
But minus an arm or two, we keep everyone as alive as possible
除了凍斷一兩根手臂 我們要盡可能保證大家活著
so Audrey stays as alive as possible.
這樣 奧德麗才能活著
- Of course. - And you too, my dear.
-明白 -你也一樣 親愛的
- That's been guaranteed,
這是答應了的
hasn't it?
不是嗎
Bye, Javi.
再見 哈維
- Rules.
規矩
The resistance is not so constrained.
抵抗軍可沒這么規矩
Every game has rules, Kevin. Get creative.
凱文 所有游戲都有規矩 有點創意嘛
Jackboot Tyson.
軍靴泰森
- Can you get me out of compost or not?
你到底能不能把我調出堆肥區
One more week.
再等一周
But in the meantime, how about a nice hot bath?
不過 趁等的時候 洗個熱水盆浴怎么樣
You taking the piss?
你是在取笑我嗎
Bathing token for services to the cause.
沐浴券 獎勵你為抵抗事業作出的貢獻
- What can we do for you, Kevin?
凱文 要喝點什么嗎
Ovaltine.
給我來杯阿華田
Yeah, we don't have Ovaltine. We have train-made hooch.
我們這里沒有阿華田 只有列車自釀的烈酒
- Fine. One hooch.
好吧 來一杯那個酒
Mr. Wilford loves what you've done with the place,
威爾福德先生很喜歡 你們打理這里的方式
but I'm afraid he needs just a smidge more from the deal.
不過 他需要你們多做一件事
Information?
打聽消息
- The subversives continue filching and currying favor
抵抗軍在不停地 各處討好 盜取資源
while their shot caller keeps slipping through our fingers.
而他們的首領 則不斷從我們指縫里溜走
We would like this person identified and captured... now.
我們現在希望能找出并抓住這個人
- Maybe our passed-out Jack knows something.
也許喝醉的那個軍靴知道點內幕
Jackboot Whiggins?
軍靴惠金斯
Oi, Stuie.
嘿 斯圖
Wake up, Whiggins. - What?
-惠金斯 醒一醒 -干嗎
You said I could stay.
你說我可以待在這里的
- They put you on Water Security, yeah? Yes.
-你是負責看守水資源的吧  -嗯 怎么了
- You're a former Firstie, so you'll be glad to help.
你以前是頭等車廂的 所以你會樂意幫忙的
- Well, what's happening in Water Security?
水資源的安全出了什么問題
Uh, you know, nothing.
沒有問題啊
Yeah.
嗯
Um, well,
好吧…
you know, very little.
只是很小的問題
Kevin doesn't need much. - Just a little thread to pick.
-凱文需要的不多 -只需要一點線索就行
Come on.
說吧
- Well, I've heard that the Second Class Watermaster
好吧 我聽說二等車廂的配水員
was giving away hot baths
在給為抵抗軍效力的人…
for service to the resistance.
提供免費熱水盆浴
Let's have a look.
我們來看看
Oh, that's healing nicely.
傷口恢復得很不錯
Have you applied your cream today?
你今天涂藥膏了嗎
- No, sir. - Well, then allow me.
-沒有 先生 -那就讓我來幫你涂吧
Oh, it's all right, cub. It's all right. You like me now.
沒事的 乖狗狗 沒事的 躺下
This business with Jupiter.
朱庇特的事
I know she's a blunt tool, Javier.
哈維爾 我知道 用它對付人的手法很粗暴
But when you're one man responsible for nearly 3,000...
可是 當你一個人 得為近三千人負責時
It's not enough being a disciplinarian.
光是紀律嚴明是不夠的
You need to add a little chaos to the mix.
我得再用上別的手段才行
In here, it's Jupiter.
在這里 就是朱庇特
Out there, it's Kevin, gnashing his teeth and running amok.
在外面 就是凱文 咬牙切齒 橫沖直撞
You can't fight the unpredictable, Javier.
哈維爾 你無法與不可預測的事情作對
That's how I keep everyone safe.
這就是我確保大家安全的方法
Anyway...
總之
I hope you see it for what it is.
我希望你能看清問題的本質
I do need you, Javier.
我確實很需要你 哈維爾
Good man.
好小伙子
Wilford.
我是威爾福德
Sir, we have a lead.
先生 我們有線索了
Watermaster Arnoldo Reyas.
配水員阿諾多雷耶斯
Clean as a baby.
清新如洗
Come on.
來吧
Come on out before you get cold.
出來吧 別著涼了
- The Watermaster told them where we are.
配水員把我們的位置告訴了他們
- Gotta go. - Again.
-得換地方了 -又要換
- Okay. - Okay.
-好了嗎  -好了
- Come on. - I'm coming.
-來吧 -來了
- There you go, that's it.
這就對了 就是這樣
- Oh. - No, no, no, no, no, no. Ruth, let's go, quick. Quick, quick, quick, quick, quick.
不 我們走吧 快
- All right. All right.
知道了
We can't all be built like a bloody whippet.
不是所有人都像你行動這么迅速
Come on. Come on.
來吧
We gotta go!
我們得走了
- Let's go. Let's go!
走吧
End of the line. The First is too frozen for the subtrain.
終點站到了 當然 這里都結冰了 通勤車不能通行
Okay.
好
Crikey, it's cold.
天啊 這里真冷
Just wait.
好 等一下
- They were here. Right under our noses.
他們在這里待過 就在我們的眼皮底下
Treachery.
背信棄義
- Who are you,
你個機靈鬼
you clever thing?
你是誰
- They got it on trickle, stays around minus 25.
他們把這里的供熱調得很低 一直都在零下25度
I'm hoping they won't look back here, because, you know, it's too cold to live.
我希望他們不會找到這里來 因為這里太冷 沒法生活
Oh, my God.
我的天
What, Kevin couldn't put anything away?
怎么 凱文就不能把這里收拾一下
In here, Ruth.
魯絲 在這里面
Watch your head.
當心頭
Had a couple of our comrades gussy it up for ya.
我找了幾個同志替你布置了一下
See, minus 12.
看 零下12度
- It's lovely, thank you. - Yeah.
真不錯 謝謝你
- Send my regards down the line.
替我轉達一下謝意
- What?
怎么了
What, you likey that I'm built like a whippet?
你喜歡我這機靈的身板嗎
- No. Mind your cheek.
什么呀 放尊重點
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
-謝謝你 -不客氣
- If you're out there, Mr. Layton,
雷頓先生 如果你在外面
now would be a great time to come home.
現在是回來的好時機
"Snowpiercer,"
雪國列車
come in. "Snowpiercer."
雪國列車 收到請回答
Oh, shit.
糟糕
Hey, buddy.
嘿 伙計
You bring your surfboard?
你帶上沖浪板了嗎
- Thought we'd do some sledding instead.
我想著還是改滑雪橇的好
Hey, what's your suit at, man?
兄弟 你的防護服還能撐多久
- 7:45.
7分45秒
The Engine.
機車怎么樣了
- Don't worry about the Engine. Alex is on it. Where are you hurting, Ben?
別為機車操心 艾莉在處理呢 本 你有哪里疼嗎
Bit of pain in the chest.
胸口有點疼
- Can you move your fingers and toes?
手指和腳趾能動嗎
- All right.
很好
I'm coming down. - Too risky, Layton.
-我這就下去 -太危險了 雷頓
Send down a rope.
放根繩子下來…
- Oh, man. Don't worry about it. You sit tight, man. I'll be right back.
你別操心了 你等著 我馬上回來
They're venting?
他們在排放燃料
They're just rolling fast enough to cool down. - I don't--I don't get it.
他們只是在緩緩前進 給引擎降溫 我不明白為什么要這樣做
- I do. - I don't think they got back on.
-我明白 -我覺得他們沒回來
What are you talking about? - So who's outside?
-你在說什么呢  -都有誰在外面
- I don't know. You think they tell me anything?
我不知道 你覺得他們有事會告訴我嗎
I know Ben went out.
我知道本之前下車了
- Yeah, well, I think I saw two more from my window.
我從我房間的窗口 看到另有兩個人下去了
- Well, then Alex has to be driving. Did she ditch them?
那準是艾莉在駕駛列車 她拋棄他們了嗎
They're not answering. Martin, it's time.
-他們沒接電話 -馬汀 是時候了
Yeah. Okay. What about Till?
行 好 那提爾怎么辦
- Well, we'll just have to go to the Engine and find out.
我們只能先去機車 看情況再說
What's happening?
這是怎么回事
We have to get back with the other train.
我們得回去跟另一列列車匯合
Help us, and I won't tell Wilford you've been cooperating.
如果你幫忙 我就不告訴威爾福德 你很配合他們的事
Are you serious right now?
你不是認真的吧
- Deadly serious.
絕對認真
Look, we need to reconnect. Okay? What are we doing out here?
我們必須重新連接 好嗎  我們這都是在干什么
- Yeah, we've been running around aimlessly. We're running out of food.
我們在漫無目的地瞎轉悠 我們快沒食物了
Last chance.
最后一次機會
Get back with Wilford
要么回到威爾福德身邊
or dig a grave with Layton.
要么就給雷頓陪葬
Then get in the cage.
那就進牢房去
What's our speed?
現在的時速是多少
Um, 75. - Okay, let's switch places;
-75公里 -好 我們交換一下
I need you over here while I start the cooling sequence.
我起動冷卻程序時 你得待在這里
Okay, you're gonna match these lines.
你得給這些電線配對
Blue to blue, red to red, and so on, you got it?
藍色接藍色 紅色接紅色 諸如此類 明白了嗎
- Yeah.
明白
- Be sure, Brakeman, okay? - These currents are live.
制動員 你得確定哦 這些線是帶電的
- Yeah, match the colors. I got it. Let's go.
確定 對顏色嘛 我能行 換吧
And I'm not a freaking Brakeman.
還有 我不是該死的制動員
Hey.
嘿
Okay, well, just in case they ask, you forced me to let you out.
萬一他們問起來 就說是你逼我放你出來的
- Hey. Time?
伙計 還剩多少時間
- Two minutes.
2分鐘
- All right, not to worry, brother. There's plenty to go around.
好 別擔心 兄弟 有足夠的時間
Not too much, Layton.
不多了 雷頓
Let's not both run out.
別弄得咱倆都沒時間了
Hey.
嗯
Hey, hey. All that surf stuff you talking, you really do that?
嘿 你之前說沖浪的事 你真的沖過浪
Bennet.
本奈特
- Surfing? - Yeah.
-沖浪的事  -對
Yeah, I spent a summer in Sopelana when I was 16.
我16歲時 在索佩拉納待過一個夏天
Yeah, the locals surfed a wave called El Bordillo.
當地人會沖一種叫“馬路牙子”的浪
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
-是嗎  -是的
I learned more on that wave than in seven years of university.
我在那浪尖上學到的 比大學七年學的都多
You ever go back?
你后來回去過嗎
Yeah, once.
嗯 回去過一次
By then, the rising sea levels
-再去的時候 海平面已上升… -好
changed the coastline.
…改變了海岸線
The wave was gone.
海浪沒有了
- Shouldn't we start going back?
我們該往回開了吧
We're still too rich.
空燃比還是太低
- Well, how long? - I don't--I don't know.
-那要等多久  -我不知道
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, Alex, you can do this.
嘿 艾莉 你能處理好的
- Okay? - I can't.
-好嗎  -我不行
What would Melanie do?
如果換作梅蘭妮 她會怎么做
- She would just know the answer. That's what she would do.
她會直接知道答案
Okay, fine, then.
好吧 那…
What would--What would Ben do?
如果換了是本呢
- He would grab a pen and paper and start mansplaining.
他會拿上紙和筆 邊畫邊解釋給你聽
- Okay, good. Just--just talk it out, then.
好 很好 那就大聲把問題列出來吧
- Built to work at speed, under load,
當初設計這引擎 是為了在負載下高速行駛
but we have neither.
但我們既沒負載也沒速度
We're a jet engine strapped to a toy wagon.
它成了被困在玩具車上的噴氣發動機
All we have to do is stop on a dime
我們只需急剎車兩次
without stalling or burning up twice and once in reverse.
確保不拋錨 也不耗盡燃料 其中一次反向即可
All right, Till, there's a three-minute window to reverse back to them.
提爾 我們有三分鐘的時間 可以倒回去接他們
Have you been avoiding me?
你一直在躲著我嗎
- I told them to lock you in the meat locker.
我讓他們把你關在冷藏室里
They thought the library was more secure. So much for that.
他們覺得關在圖書館更安全 如今看來 安全個屁
Are they all outside?
他們都在外面嗎
- I'm a bit busy right now, Audrey.
奧德麗 我現在有點忙
Well, I can see that.
我能看得出來
Look. Look. Look, what I have.
看呀 看看我有什么
Look!
看啊
I had it on me when they took me hostage.
他們抓我當人質時 它就在我身上了
I have been waiting six months for this moment.
我等了六個月 就為了這一刻
Now let's talk about going home to Daddy.
現在 讓我們談談 回去找“爹地”的事吧
- Hold on tight, buddy. I'll see you up there. - Josie, let's go.
抓緊了 我們到上面見 喬西 開始拉吧
All right, Ben.
好了 本
Here you go.
可以了
All right. Nearly there, Ben. Nearly there. There, it's done.
好 本 就差一點了 成了
Over the edge, that's it.
你上來了 好了
- Josie, throw me the switch and start back with him.
喬西 把開關扔給我 把他送回去
- No, not till you're out of there. He's fading, Josie. Get going. I'll catch up.
-不行 你不上來 我們不走 -他快不行了 快走 我會趕上的
What's your suit at? - Plenty. Don't worry about it.
-你的防護服還能撐多久  -足夠久 別擔心
I'm right behind you.
我隨后就回去
Okay.
好了
Hello.
有人嗎
Layton, come in, Layton.
雷頓 收到請回答 雷頓
- Your mother didn't make it, Alex.
你媽死了 艾莉
And that idea of an oasis out there died with her.
外面有綠洲的那個想法 也隨她而去了
No, it hasn't.
沒有隨她而去
- Well, I think you would all be getting along much better
我覺得如果你們發現了什么的話
if you discovered anything.
你們幾個的關系會好很多
- Well, you have no idea what we've discovered.
你根本不知道我們發現了什么
- Wilford has the answers, Alex.
威爾福德有解決方法 艾莉
Just keep going, and you solve everything.
繼續開 就能解決一切問題
Just keep going.
繼續開就是
No, don't.
不 不要
Get away from her.
離她遠點
Alex, you gotta go back.
艾莉 我們得回去
- Ahead, Alex. Back home to him.
往前開 艾莉 回他那里去
- We can't leave them out there.
我們不能把他們丟在外面
- Don't listen to her bleeding heart, Alex.
什么爛好人 艾莉 別聽她的
Just do the calculus of survival like Joseph would.
學一學約瑟夫 算算存活率
- Stop! Both of you, just stop!
夠了 你們倆都閉嘴
Shit.
見鬼
Just go ahead!
只管繼續往前開
Alex.
艾莉
Alex, stop the train. What if she was right?
-把列車停下 -萬一她是對的怎么辦
What if Wilford is the best bet? - He's not.
-萬一威爾福德是最好的選擇呢  -他不是
Melanie is.
梅蘭妮才是
Okay? We can get through this, Alex.
好嗎 我們可以熬過這一關的 艾莉
Don't tip it the wrong way.
別選錯了方向
Okay? Yeah.
好嗎 好
- "Snowpiercer." Come in, "Snowpiercer."
雪國列車 收到請回答 雪國列車
Layton, Layton, can you read me?
雷頓 你聽到了嗎
Layton.
雷頓
"Snowpiercer," come in.
雪國列車 收到請回答
Shit.
糟糕
There. There they are.
在那里 他們在那里
There's only two-- there's only two of them.
我只看到兩個人 只有兩個人
- Wait, wait. - Sit there.
-等一下 我的胸部 -坐在那里
Layton, come in, Layton.
雷頓 收到請回答 雷頓
Layton,
雷頓
come in, Layton.
雷頓 收到請回答
Look, I'll be back, okay?
聽著 我會回來的 好嗎
- Josie, you've been out too long.
喬西 你在外面待得太久了
- I can find him. I'll be back.
我能找到他的 我去去就回
- Josie, his suit ran out five minutes ago.
喬西 他的防護服五分鐘前就沒電了
Layton. Layton!
雷頓
- What? What?
怎么了
He's there? - Yes. - He's there? He's there.
-他在外面嗎 他在嗎  -是的 他在
So what can I get you?
你想要什么
- I'd say I've got everything I ever wanted.
我會說 我想要的一切我都有了
A girl,
一個女朋友
a club,
一間夜總會
and the gratitude of the great Mr. Wilford.
還有偉大的威爾福德先生的感激
Come on.
過來
- Wouldn't we all love a nice warm bath?
誰不想洗個舒適的熱水澡呢
These two stole hot water resources from you for the resistance.
這兩個家伙為了抵抗軍 從你們這里竊取了熱水
Because they had to be clean...
因為他們要干凈…
You go unwashed.
…你們就沒澡洗了
You first.
你先來
It's all right.
沒事的
It was worth it.
那是值得的
- Well, I hate to miss a public defiling,
我也不想錯過公開羞辱的儀式
but the proceedings are rather foregone, aren't they?
但儀式早就開始多時了吧
I'd much rather be here with my friends, embarking on a fresh path.
我更愿意和朋友們 一起在這里 踏上一條新的征程